So binary search is an algorithm for searching through elements of a spree sorted array.
It's very important, pretty short there because so there we are going to search for number six.
Let's try for this array to find the six.
We look at the number in the center of the array.
In this case, it's five.
So we divide the array and we compare five to the number six that we were searching for because five
is less than six.
We know that the number six is to the right of five.
So from that candidates, we removed numbers that are no longer needed.
This is the first step.
The second step.
We need to remove the numbers that are no longer needed.
Again, we look at the numbers in the center of the remaining area, which is seven seven is greater
than six.
So the numbers and the candidates.
To the right of the seven are not needed.
So we removed the numbers and they are no longer needed.
From the candidates, we remove the numbers that are narrowly needed and we do now and we look at the
number six is the number and the center of the remaining area.
This time it's number six.
So six equal to six.
So we've found the number that we are looking for in this way.
We see that binary search makes use of pre sorted array and continuously have the numbers to search
through all, allowing it to search for numbers efficiently.
So this is is that binary search.
And I hope you learned from this video and all of the course, and I want from you to make us a favor
that rating us five stars on Udemy.
So let's move to see how to implement the binary search in C language in interactive way and recursive
way.
And let's solve the same exercises and Java.